surprise,   in   2009   it's   revealed   that   the   government   has
been   cooking   the   books   and   its   budget   deficit   is
not   6.7%,   but   double   that.   (clears throat)   Whoops.
[...content omitted...]
172%   by   2011   with   creditors   quickly   draining   the   bailout
causing   unrest   at   home   with   Greeks   bearing   the   burden
of   falling   wages,   rising   taxes,   and   unemployment   above   25%.
So,   when   a   snap   election   occurs   in   2015,   the
people   break   over   40   years   of   two-party   rule   and
elect   a   new   anti-austerity   party   to   office   in   a
bid   for   change.   The   new   prime   minister   promises   to
boost   spending   and   throw   down   the   gauntlet   to   the
Troika   to   renegotiate   terms,   raising   tensions   between   the   government
and   the   Troika   until   the   country's   lifeline   snaps   and,
ladies   and   gentlemen,   all   hell   breaks   loose.
Creditors   flee   Greece   once   again   and   a   liquidity   crisis
emerges   with   fear   gripping   the   country   amid   concerns   of
Grexit,   Greece's   departure   from   the   EU.   Negotiations   with   the
Troika   fall   through   as   even   its   members   clash.
And   on   June   30th,   2015,   with   the   government   unable
to   secure   any   further   debt   relief,   Greece   defaults,   missing
a   1.6   billion   Euro   debt   payment   to   the   IMF;
the   first   developed   country   to   ever   do   so.
The   foundation   of   Greece's   economy   begins   to   crack   as
the   government   shuts   down   its   stock   exchange   and   banking
system.   Greeks   continue   to   fight   against   a   new   bailout
proposed   by   the   EU,   but   at   this   point,   with
the   country   in   financial   purgatory,   Grexit   inching   closer,   and
no   more   leverage   for   negotiation,   on   July   16th   a
very   desperate   government   throws   in   the   towel,   grabbing   ahold
of   the   EU's   third   lifeline   and   accepting   an   86
billion   Euro   bailout   in   August.   And   so,   with   the
fight   to   boost   spending   meeting   a   dramatic   end,   the